#### Juliana Nocchi Dobal

I am a career changer junior software engineer who enjoys working on projects from start to finish. During my 16-week bootcamp I worked with front end languages and frameworks such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and React Native to create stunning user interfaces; back end technologies and frameworks, including NodeJS and ExpressJS; database management systems, such as PostgreSQL and MongoDB; and version control to collaborate effectively with other developers on large-scale projects.

I value continuous learning and I am passionate about building strong relationships. I believe that collaboration, communication, and respect are essential for any successful project. For highlights of my professional skills from peers and managers, please have a look at my <u>LinkedIn Recommendations</u>.

### **Projects**

# Solved (Treasure hunting App)

This mobile app consists of a live-action treasure hunting with clues to help the user to search for five secret London landmarks. I was involved in the ideation, designing the user Interface and all images, prototyping the screens, implementing functionalities on the front end, data manipulation, integration testing and styling. We utilised Node.js, Express and MongoDB Atlas to build the back end, React Native on the front end, and Jest for testing. Made API calls to 2 different services and used image recognition to ensure they arrived at the correct locations.

# Acebook-Air (Social Media Platform)

This application consists of a back end API built with Express and a front end built with React. It allows users to create profiles with a picture, share and like posts, and update their personal details. I was involved in end-to-end and component testing (Cypress), developing the home page and navbar, adding routes and styling various pages.

### **Tech Experience**

### Makers Academy - 16-week Software Development Bootcamp, London - UK

### Career Changer Student (Nov 2022 - Mar 2023)

- Awarded a full scholarship with Codebar & Makers Represent Scholarship Programme
- Designed and built 17 web applications using **Ruby** and **Javascript**, with emphasis on self-led learning, which allowed me to become adaptable to new technologies
- Collaborated in Agile teams with a focus on XP values, pair programming, Object Oriented Development (OOD), Test-driven Development (TDD) and Git workflow, to ensure our code was robust, maintainable, and efficient
- Developed, as part of a group of 5, a live-action treasure-hunting mobile app (called Solved) with clues to help the user to search for five secret London landmarks. Utilised **Node.js**, **Express** and **MongoDB Atlas** to build the back end, **React Native** on the front end, and **Jest** for testing. Made **API calls** to 2 different services and used **image recognition** to make sure they arrived at the correct locations
- Created a social media platform (Acebook-Air), a host/guest website (CloudBnB), and a website to showcase projects (<u>Pensano</u> under construction). Further details on these projects can be found on my <u>GitHub</u> page

Skills: Ruby, JavaScript, Backend Web Development, Frontend Development, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL, Express.js, React.js, Code Review, Jest, RSpec, Cypress, Diagramming and Prototyping.

### **Professional Experience**

## **VTEX** - Ecommerce Platform, London - UK

## EMEA Chief of Staff & Office Manager (Jun 2021 - Aug 2022)

- Managed the HR platform (EMEA ~90 employees), initiated processes/changes, reviewed/approved requests, and coordinated day-to-day functions from onboarding to offboarding
- Managed activities in 6 European offices (London, Paris, Milan, Bucharest, Barcelona and Lisbon). Initiating the purchasing flow (office supplies, equipment, food, etc.), negotiating contracts, communicating with suppliers, tracking expenses, and managing the region's budget; working closely with the Procurement, Legal, Finance and Controllership teams
- Mentored new Office Manager and Chief of Staff globally
- Contacted speakers and hosted weekly training for the Sales Enablement team, including Sales & Merchandising, Finance & Accounting, Supply Chain & Operations, Technology & Data, Digital Marketing

## Brazilian Naval Commission in Europe (BNCE) - Brazilian Navy Procurement Office, London - UK

## Senior HR Generalist & Immigration Adviser (Feb 2015 - May 2021)

- Was the primary contact for all UK visa enquiries (~300 processes, including family members)
- Developed & implemented strategies, policies and other initiative programmes
- Prepared and presented semiannual onboarding and offboarding sessions to ~20 Diplomatic staff
- · Managed all aspects of onboarding and offboarding, and the workforce management system

## **Education & Languages**

**Post Graduation in Animation** (Feb 2006 - Dec 2006) - Distinction Pontifical Catholic University, Rio de Janeiro - BR

**Ba - Bachelor of Arts** (Mar 2002 - Dec 2005) - Distinction Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro - BR

**English**: Full professional proficiency • **Portuguese**: Native proficiency

#### **Additional information**

- Regular attendee of Creative Mornings, the world's largest face-to-face creative community
- · Volunteer at Codebar, programming workshops for under represented groups in tech
- Other interests: Travelling, Functional Nutrition, Playing Volleyball & Watercolour Painting